>> Jem Young: 最着名的集装箱化平台
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: The most famous
containerization platform you've probably
是 Docker。
heard of is Docker.
这很适合它是鲸鱼
It's fitting that it's a whale.
因为它是
Because it is.
当你思考容器时，你会想到 Docker。
When you think containers,
you're thinking Docker.
Amazon 拥有自己的 Amazon Elastic Container 服务。
Amazon has their own
Amazon Elastic Container Service.
Apache Mesos 是另一个
Apache Mesos is another one.
CoreOS rkt是另一个集装箱化服务。
And CoreOS rkt, known as Rocket,
is another containerization service.
集装箱化仅意味着在应用程序之间进行对话的层
And containerization just means it's that
layer that talks between the application
和操作系统。
and the operating system.
你可以把它移到周围，这只是一层。
And you can move that around,
it's just one layer.
所以我可以有一层，但很多应用，都是工作，
So I can have one layer, but
many applications, and they all work,
而不是虚拟机，它是每个容器的操作系统。
rather than a virtual machine, which is an
operating system per individual container.
Netflix 有它自己的，很好。
Netflix has its own and
it works pretty well.
我们运行了数百万个容器和数以千计的服务器。
We run millions of containers and
thousands of servers.
因此，这是大多数人永远不会得到的规模，所以别担心。
So it's a scale that most people will
never get to, so don't worry about it.
这就是为什么我们不能在这里做任何实际的集装箱化
That's why we're not going to do
any actual containerization here,
因为如果你是那么大的
because if you're at that scale,
你可能需要知道比我今天要教你的还要多
you'll probably need to know a bit
more than I'm gonna teach you today.
但很高兴知道一个容器是什么，它是如何运作的。
But it's good to know what a container is,
how it works.
Netflix 在一个名为 Titus 的平台上运行，这就是我们的集装箱化。
Netflix runs on a platform called Titus,
and that does our containerization.
而且效果很好
And it works pretty well and
如果你的公司有兴趣调查它是公开的
it's open source if your company
is interested in looking into it.
>> Jem Young: 所以我谈到了集装箱化，
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: So
I talked about containerization, and
那就好了
that's all well and good.
但如何处理成千上万个容器，百万个容器?
But how do you roll out thousands of
containers, millions of containers?
您需要编排某种编排。
You need some sort of orchestration.
Czuz 我不能只复制粘贴，然后用一堆服务器来运行。
Cuz I can't just copy paste and
then run that against a bunch of servers.
我需要某种形式的传导
I need some sort of way
of conducting that.
这就是为什么叫编排
That's why it's called orchestration,
因为您需要确保正确安装操作系统。
because you need to make sure the
operating systems are installed correctly.
您需要确保已安装容器化平台
You need to make sure your
containerization platform is installed
正确。
correctly.
这很像交响乐，就像这里是弦，
And it's a lot like a symphony,
where it's like here are the strings,
这里是大提琴，是黄铜，他们都进来了，一起来了
here's the cello, here's the brass, and
they all come in and it comes together and
然后交响乐就会播放这就是为什么它被称为编排
then the symphony plays out, and
that's why it's called orchestration.
当你把它卷出来，说实话，它很漂亮，你可以看到一个完整的集群
And when you roll it out, honestly, it's
beautiful, and you see an entire cluster
因为他们从旧的集群中切换过来了
turn green because they switched
over from the old cluster.
我不知道也许晚点我会给你看一些截屏
And it's, I don't know, maybe later,
I'll show you some screenshots of some of
我们是怎么把东西滚出去的因为它真的很棒
how we roll things out,
because it's really impressive.
但你需要一个把所有这些容器和
But you need a way of taking
all these containers and
所有这些单独的操作系统并将它们应用于服务器本身。
all these individual operating systems and
applying them to the servers itself.
仅仅说，我跑的是容器，很酷。
It's not enough to just say,
I run containers, cool.
但千万次你会发现奇怪的虫子
But do that a million times and
you're going to discover weird bugs and
有负载平衡的奇怪的东西
weird things with load balancing.
更不用说，我们讨论了弹性计算。
Not to mention,
we talked about elastic computing.
所以如果我需要一万个容器，有多少台服务器 ?
So if I need 10,000 more containers,
how many servers is that?
我不知道我不知道 我不知道
I don't know.
I don't
了解每个容器需要多少资源。
know how much resources
each container needs.
我不知道服务器有多少资源。
And I don't know how much
resources the server has.
所以我们有这个编排层说，哎，我有一个 Node 应用程序，
So we have this orchestration layer that
says, hey, I have a Node application and
我需要的是 200 个 RAM 和 10 兆字节的硬盘空间。
I need, let's say 200 megs of RAM and
about 10 megabytes hard drive space.
我知道服务器需要多少。
I know how much the server needs.
我可以把这些都滚出去
And I can roll these out.
我可以在服务器上均匀滚动
And I can roll these out
evenly across the servers so
没有一个服务器正在占用所有流量。
that no one server is
taking all the traffic.
这就是编排的内容。
And that's what the orchestration does.
你要听的最有名的就是库伯内特
The famous one you're
gonna hear is Kubernetes.
那是屋子里的大号
That's the big one in the room.
速记为 K8s。
The shorthand is K8s.
所以如果你看到它，它指的是库伯内特。
So if you ever see that,
it's referring to Kubernetes.
因为，它是一个很长的名字，我不知道它是什么意思。
Because, well, it's a long name that
I don't actually know what it means.
有人知道这意味着什么吗
Anybody know what it means?
那是什么意思
What does it mean, please?
>> Student : k 和 s 之间有八个字符。
&gt;&gt; Student: There's eight
characters between k and s.
> > Jem Young: 不，不，我知道
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: No, no, I know that.
库伯内特是什么意思
What does Kubernetes mean?
这意味着什么吗
Does it mean anything?
我不知道我不知道
I don't know.
我可以查一查
I could probably look this up.
>> Student2: 在 Twitter 上有一个笑话，它是以支出之神命名的。
&gt;&gt; Student2: There's a joke on Twitter
that it's named after the god of spending
在云中的钱
money in the cloud.
>> Jem Young: [LAUGH] 是。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: [LAUGH] Yes.
我是说我不知道
I mean, I don't know.
也许这就是它的意思 但你有时会看到 K8s
Maybe that's what it means.
But you'll see K8s sometimes.
再来一次我得把你的书呆子给我
Again, I gotta get your
nerd credit up here.
你就像我在用 K8s
So you're like, yeah, I'm using K8s.
但这只是一个编排层。
But it's just an orchestration layer.
与 Docker不同， Docker是一个容器程序， Kubernetes 是控制
So unlike Docker, which is a
containerizer, Kubernetes is what controls
滚出所有你要部署的集装箱
the rolling out of all these
containers you're deploying.
还有 Docker Swarm ，他们有他们的，也是一个大玩家。
There's also Docker Swarm, they have
their, that's also a big player too.
下一个是 Amazon Elastic Kubernetes 服务。
The next one would be
Amazon Elastic Kubernetes service.
Apache Mesos 是一个容器程序和编排层。
Apache Mesos is a containerizer and
an orchestration layer.
还有 AKS ，我认为是微软的。
Then there's AKS,
which I think is Microsoft's.
他们有自己的 Azure ， Kubernetes 服务，
They have their own Azure,
Kubernetes service, something like that,
有些人用的
which some people use.
但有趣的是我们现在有集装箱了
But it's funny that we are like,
we have containers now, and
然后我们就有弹性计算
then we have elastic computing.
但没有人认为，我们需要一个控制所有这些事物的方法。
But no one thought, well, we need
a way of controlling all these things.
因为现在不是一台服务器，而是一百万台服务器。
Because now instead of one server,
we have a million servers.
所以它真的很复杂得非常快
So it gets really,
really complicated really fast.
但我要说的是当你在这个工程的时候
But I'll say this,
when you're at this level of engineering,
你在 DevOps 的土地上更少的堆，更多的 DevOps。
you're in DevOps land,
less full stack, more DevOps.
你要知道你在做什么
And you need to know
precisely what you're doing,
因为你带来了价值数千美元的服务器
because you're bringing up thousands
of dollars worth of servers and
很快就会开始你需要知道如何平衡这一点
taking down very quickly, and
you need to know how to balance that.
但我不想再插 Netflix 了
But I don't want to plug Netflix anymore.
但我们的速度如此之快我不会说
But we've gotten so
fast at, I won't say we,
我和它没什么关系，比我更聪明的人，但是他们有
I have nothing to do with it, much smarter
people than me, but they've got so
很快就会得到数百万的服务
fast at taking out millions of services
and taking them down very quickly.
我们可以在 7 分钟内从西部到东部
We can roll over from uswest to us
east one region in seven minutes.
这就是交通量的十亿字节
So that's gigabytes of traffic,
数百万的连接上百万的容器
millions of millions of connections,
millions of containers,
我们可以很快地将这些信息滚动到一个真正的立体编排层
we can roll those over very quickly due
to a really solid orchestration layer.
然后当区域重新上线时我们可以把这些都搬回来
And then when the region comes back
online, we can move all those back and
人们不注意
people don't notice.
我们一直都这么做
We do it all the time.
这就是一个非常好的编排层的力量。
That's the power of like a really
good orchestration layer.